In this lecture, we're going to look at a few more AWS services
in the area of security, governance, and compliance.
So the first one is Amazon Inspector.
So Amazon Inspector automatically
discovers compute workload, such as Amazon EC2, instances,
container images in ECR and within CACD and Lambda function.
Now, what does the Amazon Inspector do?
It scans for software vulnerabilities
and unintended network exposure.
In the exam, you need to keep in mind two things
about Amazon Inspector.
One, it is for compute workloads.
Second, it scans for software vulnerabilities
and unintended network exposure.
OK, just let me just show you through the console quick.
So if I just go and search for Inspector.
So right now, you can see I am not enabled Amazon Inspector.
So we need to activate the Inspector in order for it to work.
And there's going to be some charge for it.
So I'm not going to activate Inspector.
But you can see here Amazon Inspector
is an automated vulnerability management
service that consistently scans workloads for vulnerabilities
and unintended network exposure.
So if you activate Inspector, then it's
going to scan all your compute workloads
and then generate a report for you.
Now, let's take a look at the second service,
which is AWS trusted advisor.
So AWS trusted advisor continuously
evaluates your AWS environment using best practices
along multiple categories.
So those categories are cost optimization
and security.
Then you have resilience, performance, operational excellence.
Then you have another really important one, which
is called as service limits.
So what AWS trusted advisor does is it
will review how you are using all the AWS services
within your account across these six different categories
and then compare them with the AWS best practices.
And then it would recommend actions to remediate
any deviations from best practices.
Now, let's take a look at all these six different categories
from the console.
So I am on the AWS console.
Let me just search for trusted advisor.
Now on the left, you can see recommendations.
And here are the six categories.
So if I just click on cost optimization.
So here it defines what it means by cost optimization.
Choose a check name to see recommendations
for a ways to help save money for your AWS account.
So now these are the various best practices
that it would check the resource that you are using
and see if it is cost optimized.
So in my case, I don't have an ECR repository.
If I had configured one, then it would check
whether I have Amazon ECR repository without a life cycle
policy, then it will check whether the AWS account is part
of AWS organization or not, whether my EBS volumes
are overprovision.
So if they are overprovision, it would recommend
to reduce the size of the EBS volume.
The second one is the performance.
And here it will recommend how to improve the performance
of AWS services.
It will check if Amazon DynamoDB auto scaling
has been enabled.
It will check Amazon EBS is underprovision.
So it will look at all the AWS services
that I have provision and compare it with the best practices
and then give me some recommendations.
So I don't have any of these services provision right now.
So that's why it's graying out these areas.
But this is what is gonna check this.
So similarly for security, it will give me suggestions
on how to improve the security posture for my infrastructure.
It will check if there are any Amazon EBS public snapshots,
Amazon RDS public snapshots, obviously you should not have
public snapshots of your database.
Then it will look at fault tolerance
and here it will suggest ways to increase their availability
and redundancy of my services.
So it will take a look at Amazon DynamoDB
point in time recovery, Amazon Redshift cluster,
automated snapshots and a lot of other things.
Then we have the service limits.
I think this is the most important use case
for trusted advisor where it would give an alert
if any of the services reach 80% of the service quota.
So what it means is like if you see for each AWS service,
let's take the example of revenue function in most accounts
and regions, you have the limit of about 1000 invocations.
And if the invocations hit more than 1000,
then there's going to be throttling.
So if you're expecting that the invocations
are going to be more than 1000.
So what you can do is you can go to this link service quota
or raise a ticket for AWS support center,
where you can request for additional invocations.
So what AWS does is let's say for lambda function
and let's say the quota limit is 1000.
So when you reach 80% of the limit,
it will send you an yellow alert.
If you reach 100% then it will send you a red alert.
Okay, then finally you have the operational excellence
where it helps you improve the operational readiness
of your resources.
And these are some of the things from operational perspective
that it will evaluate against the AWS best practice.
So Amazon, VPC without flow logs and many others.
So from the exam perspective,
what you need to remember is that there is a service called
as trusted advisor, which will evaluate all the resources
within your AWS account and map them
to the AWS best practices along these six different areas.
And if there is a deviation,
then it is good to provide recommendations and alert you.
Okay, that's pretty much it from this lecture.
I'll see in the next lecture. Thank you.